<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Biología Evolutiva on Pablo Marcos' Blog</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/biolog%C3%ADa-evolutiva/</link><description>Recent content in Biología Evolutiva on Pablo Marcos' Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/biolog%C3%ADa-evolutiva/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Computational Methods to Analyse Rabies Virus Recombination and Mutation Rates</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/biolog%C3%ADa-evolutiva/exercise-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/biolog%C3%ADa-evolutiva/exercise-2/</guid><description>Abstract The Rabies Virus is one of the most terrible viruses in existence today: not only has it been tormenting mankind for years, but to this day it continues to kill more than 59000 people a year, making it one of the most neglected zoonotic diseases in existence, and one that, because of its terrible consequences, continues to be relevant to this day. In this article, we attempt to elucidate, using solely computational methods, when it emmerged.</description></item><item><title>Analyzing the probability and time of fixation of random neutral mutations in silico</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/biolog%C3%ADa-evolutiva/exercise-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/biolog%C3%ADa-evolutiva/exercise-1/</guid><description>Abstract Biological clocks are molecular mechanisms present in living organisms that allow scientists to estimate the passage of time. In this task, we will use a computer model to simulate the evolution over time of a neutral mutation appearing in the genome of a living being in a population N, analyzing its fixation capacity and the average time it takes for fixation to occur. It is precisely through these mechanisms that it is possible to analyze the passage of time since the appearance of a mutation, as has recently happened in the Juan Maeso case.</description></item></channel></rss>