<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bioinformatics Programming Challenges on Pablo Marcos' Blog</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/bioinfo-programming-challenges/</link><description>Recent content in Bioinformatics Programming Challenges on Pablo Marcos' Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/bioinfo-programming-challenges/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SPARQL Queries</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/bioinfo-programming-challenges/assignment-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/bioinfo-programming-challenges/assignment-5/</guid><description>SPARQL is a query language and protocol for searching, adding, modifying or deleting RDF (Resource Description Framework) graph data available on the Internet. Its name is a recursive acronym that stands for SPARQL Protocol and RDF Query Language. Its syntax and functionality is quite simmilar to that of SQL, given that both are designed to query large databases; the main difference is that SQL does this by accessing tables in relational databases, and SPARQL works with a web of Linked Data</description></item><item><title>Finding Orthologues in Arabidopsis Thaliana</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/bioinfo-programming-challenges/assignment-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/bioinfo-programming-challenges/assignment-4/</guid><description>The idea for this assignment is find the orthologue pairs between species Arabidopsis and S. pombe using BioRuby to do BLAST and parse the BLAST-generated reports. We will use use &amp;ldquo;reciprocal best BLAST&amp;rdquo;, scanning for Protein A of Species A in the whole proteome of Species B, and then BLAST the top hit against all proteins in Species A. If the top hits match, the protein is a good Orthologue candidate.</description></item><item><title>GFF feature files and visualization</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/bioinfo-programming-challenges/assignment-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/bioinfo-programming-challenges/assignment-3/</guid><description>Tasks: for 10% (easy) Using BioRuby, examine the sequences of the ~167 Arabidopsis genes from the last assignment by retrieving them from whatever database you wish Loop over every exon feature, and scan it for the CTTCTT sequence Take the coordinates of every CTTCTT sequence and create a new Sequence Feature. Add that new Feature to the EnsEMBL Sequence object. Once you have found and added them all, loop over each one of your CTTCTT features and create a GFF3-formatted file of these features.</description></item><item><title>Your worst nightmare</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/bioinfo-programming-challenges/assignment-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/bioinfo-programming-challenges/assignment-2/</guid><description>A recent paper executes a meta-analysis of a few thousand published co-expressed gene sets from Arabidopsis. They break these co-expression sets into ~20 sub-networks of &amp;lt;200 genes each, that they find consistently co-expressed with one another. Assume that you want to take the next step in their analysis, and see if there is already information linking these predicted sub-sets into known regulatory networks. One step in this analysis would be to determine if the co-expressed genes are known to bind to one another.</description></item><item><title>Creating Objects</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/bioinfo-programming-challenges/assignment-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/bioinfo-programming-challenges/assignment-1/</guid><description>Your task is to use Object-oriented programming to achieve two things:
&amp;ldquo;Simulate&amp;rdquo; planting 7 grams of seeds from each of the records in the seed stock genebank; then, you should update the genebank information to show the new quantity of seeds that remain after a planting. The new state of the genebank should be printed to a new file, using exactly the same format as the original file seed_stock_data.tsv. If the amount of seed is reduced to zero or less than zero, then a friendly warning message should appear on the screen.</description></item></channel></rss>