<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Genomics Assisted Breeding on Pablo Marcos' Blog</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/gab/</link><description>Recent content in Genomics Assisted Breeding on Pablo Marcos' Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/gab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DO NOT PICK THIS SUBJECT!!</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/gab/warning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/gab/warning/</guid><description>To any UPM&amp;rsquo;s Master in Computational Biology students that might be reading this, i have a strong warning to make:
DO. NOT. PICK. THIS. SUBJECT. !!!!!!! The teacher was extremely rude to the students, to the point that, after being publicly humiliated, I decided to change it for &amp;ldquo;Evolutiva&amp;rdquo;, which I found much, much nicer. I have found absolutely no one from my promotion (2021/22) that can recommend this teacher, although the subject&amp;rsquo;s contents are, in fact, interesting.</description></item><item><title>Assignment 2</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/gab/assignment-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/gab/assignment-2/</guid><description>Fundamental concepts Blending Inheritance What implications from Blending Inheritance were dismissed by Mendel? Before Mendel, people used to think that, given that both parents contribute fluids to their offspring, the descendant&amp;rsquo;s traits would be a mixture of the two individual&amp;rsquo;s characteristcs: a &amp;ldquo;common middle ground&amp;rdquo;, a central point probably influenced by Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s theory of balance.
Thus, blending inheritance proponents assumed that half the variation is removed each generation, and that this variation had to be somehow replenished by mutation.</description></item><item><title>Assignment 1</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/gab/assignment-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/gab/assignment-1/</guid><description>Crop Production What are the main disciplines that helped to increase crop production in the last century and how did they do so? In the last century, and, specially, after 1960, we have witnessed the unfolding of a green revolution, a huge increase in the yield of crops and in food production that has enabled the human race to reduce hunger even when the population to feed keeps growing. This has been possible through the use of new, higher-yelding varieties, controlled irrigation (i.</description></item></channel></rss>