<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Computational Structural Biology for Lead Discovery on Pablo Marcos' Blog</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/lead-discovery/</link><description>Recent content in Computational Structural Biology for Lead Discovery on Pablo Marcos' Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/lead-discovery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Annex I - Code</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/lead-discovery/annex-i-code/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/lead-discovery/annex-i-code/</guid><description>This jupyter notebook shall serve as accompanying material to the paper titled &amp;ldquo;Using Computational Methods to Discover Novel Drugs for the Treatment of Androgenetic Alopecia&amp;rdquo;, a report for the &amp;ldquo;Computational Structural Biology for Lead Discovery&amp;rdquo; subject at UPM&amp;rsquo;s Master in Computational Biology
Imports First, we proceed to import the modules we will use:
import json # Lets us work with the json format import requests # Allows Python to make web requests import pandas as pd # Analysis of tabular data import numpy as np # Numerical library import matplotlib.</description></item><item><title>Using Computational Methods to discover novel drugs for the treatment of Androgenetic Alopecia</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/lead-discovery/assignment-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/lead-discovery/assignment-3/</guid><description>Abstract Androgenetic alopecia is a genetic variation that causes hair loss on the scalp due to hypersensitivity of hair follicles to didydrotestosterone (DHT). Using only computational methods, we were able to find a drug candidate to replace the most commonly used drug, Finasteride (FNS), which acts by blocking the generation of DHT in the scalp by type II 5-α-reductase, the most active isoform there. Not only did we improve Ki (from 26 nM in FNS to 21 nM), but our candidate remains 63% more selective to type II than to type I, which we hope will allow it to avoid FNS’s side effects.</description></item><item><title>Designing a pharmacophore and ensuring ADMET properties</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/lead-discovery/assignment-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/lead-discovery/assignment-2/</guid><description>In the previous assignment, we managed, using ligand Based Virtual Screening, to obtain a list of those molecules that we considered to have &amp;quot;high affinity&amp;quot; with finasteride, a selective inhibitor of 5α-reductase type II, the enzyme that converts testosterone into dihydrotestosterone in the scalp and, therefore, that causes baldness. The idea was thus to find a molecule similar to finasteride and with the same properties, but even more selective and with greater affinity, in order to improve its therapeutic properties.</description></item><item><title>Designing a pharmacophore and ensuring ADMET properties</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/lead-discovery/assignment-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/lead-discovery/assignment-1/</guid><description>For this assignment, I will study Male Pattern Hair Loss, also called baldness or, more technically, alopecia. Although not technically a “disease” (it can be more accurately defined as a normal phenotipic variation) its high prevalence among caucasian men (~40% of men over 40),1 the age I am approaching and my family history, I believe this topic could be of great interest for me to investigate.
Analysis of Molecular Mechanisms Androgenetic alopecia is a hereditary condition, in which scalp hair progressively thins, and eventually stops growing, under the influence of DiHidroTestosterone, an hormone derived from Testosterone.</description></item></channel></rss>