<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Modelización de Sistemas Biológicos on Pablo Marcos' Blog</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/modelizaci%C3%B3n-de-sistemas-biol%C3%B3gicos/</link><description>Recent content in Modelización de Sistemas Biológicos on Pablo Marcos' Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/modelizaci%C3%B3n-de-sistemas-biol%C3%B3gicos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Modelling the syncronization pattern of Photinus carolinus in silico using cellular automata</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/modelizaci%C3%B3n-de-sistemas-biol%C3%B3gicos/synchronization-of-fireflies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/modelizaci%C3%B3n-de-sistemas-biol%C3%B3gicos/synchronization-of-fireflies/</guid><description>Abstract The synchronisation of bioluminescence in Photinus carolinus, the rocky mountain firefly, has intrigued researchers and visitors alike for years, making it one of the most studied phenomena of its kind. Using parameters defined in previous literature, we have created a cellular automaton capable of representing, in a simple way, the complex synchronisation mechanisms behind this coleopteran species. Using descriptive statistical methods, we concluded that the most important parameter for defining the system is the size of the network, much more so than the initial proportion of each class of individual or the ratio of influenceability by neighbours, and we were able to test the robustness of our results using Machine Learning, a completely different method that nevertheless supports the same conclusions.</description></item><item><title>Preferential Attachment Networks</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/modelizaci%C3%B3n-de-sistemas-biol%C3%B3gicos/beyond-erdos-renyi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/modelizaci%C3%B3n-de-sistemas-biol%C3%B3gicos/beyond-erdos-renyi/</guid><description>In the last exercise, we used an Erdös-Rényi random attachment model to analyze how interconnections influence the spread of illness over space. Erdös-Rényi, however, is not the only model that exists, and others, such as Preferential Attachment Networks, have the advantage of being more true to reality and an even closer representation of reality.
In these models, unlike in the random models, there is a preference when forming links between nodes: normally, nodes tend to cluster around the nodes with the largest number of linked nodes, promoting centralization and improving the connection between nodes; in this way, for example, the diameter of the network tends to decrease, since most nodes can be connected by traveling to the &amp;ldquo;mother node&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>The Erdös-Rényi model</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/modelizaci%C3%B3n-de-sistemas-biol%C3%B3gicos/networks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/modelizaci%C3%B3n-de-sistemas-biol%C3%B3gicos/networks/</guid><description>In the last assignment, we explored the role that spacial distribution played in the evolution of different functions over time, but playing with Conway&amp;rsquo;s Game of Life. This approach, though really powerful for its level of simplicity, has some issues, the most obvious being that real human beings dont live in 3x3 lattices where they only interact with their closes neighbors; rather, as we can see just by looking around at human society, some people are more connected than other, some are connected to people far away and closer home, and some are not connected at all.</description></item><item><title>Is free will or its counterpart, determinism, just a delusion?</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/modelizaci%C3%B3n-de-sistemas-biol%C3%B3gicos/essay-on-free-will/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/modelizaci%C3%B3n-de-sistemas-biol%C3%B3gicos/essay-on-free-will/</guid><description>The existence or not of free will is one of the problems that have most tormented mankind over the centuries, eliciting reactions from fields as varied as psychology, biology and physics.
The field of neurology does not seem to offer conclusive answers to this question. The Lisbet experiment, for example, demonstrated that the actions we take are previously and unconsciously decided by the brain, and that it is then that our consciousness, our &amp;ldquo;inner voice&amp;rdquo;, feels the desire to perform these actions, thus ruling out the possibility of a thinking entity outside the constraints of the physical world.</description></item><item><title>The Cellular Automata</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/modelizaci%C3%B3n-de-sistemas-biol%C3%B3gicos/celular-automata/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/modelizaci%C3%B3n-de-sistemas-biol%C3%B3gicos/celular-automata/</guid><description>A cellular automaton is a discrete model of computation consisting on a regular grid of cells, each in one of a finite number of states, such as on and off. For each cell, a set of cells called its neighborhood is defined relative to the specified cell. An initial state is selected by assigning a state for each cell. A new generation is created according to some fixed rule that determines the new state of each cell in terms of the current state of the cell and the states of the cells in its neighborhood.</description></item><item><title>The Kuramoto Oscilator Model</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/modelizaci%C3%B3n-de-sistemas-biol%C3%B3gicos/kuramoto-oscilators/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/modelizaci%C3%B3n-de-sistemas-biol%C3%B3gicos/kuramoto-oscilators/</guid><description>The Kuramoto Model is a mathematical model used to describe the synchronization of a large set of coupled oscillators. This formulation, which was motivated by the behaviour of both physical and biological oscilators, has found widespread application in neuroscience.
The model makes several assumptions, including that there is weak coupling, that the oscillators are identical or nearly identical, and that interactions depend sinusoidally on the phase difference between each pair of objects.</description></item><item><title>Analysis of the efects of Lockdowns on CoViD</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/modelizaci%C3%B3n-de-sistemas-biol%C3%B3gicos/seir-modified-model/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/modelizaci%C3%B3n-de-sistemas-biol%C3%B3gicos/seir-modified-model/</guid><description>During the COVID-19 outbreak in spring 2020, preventive confinement at day D for susceptible individuals was implemented in several countries to “bend” the infection curve and control the spread of the virus. Let us assume that confined individuals are effectively protected from infection. A “bending” or flattening of the (log-scale) curve representing the number of active cases was widely publicized as a sign that the epidemics was under control.</description></item><item><title>Studying the SIR Model</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/modelizaci%C3%B3n-de-sistemas-biol%C3%B3gicos/sir-model/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/modelizaci%C3%B3n-de-sistemas-biol%C3%B3gicos/sir-model/</guid><description>A basic SIR model, such as the one that we will now proceed to study, includes three cathegories:
Susceptibles: The individuals that may be infected Infected: The individuals currently carrying the virus, which can pass it on to the next generation Recovered: Those that have been infected, have recovered, and cannot pass on the infection (this model assumes permanent inmunity) Which relate among them using the following parameters:
$\beta$: number of infected persons per sick individual per day.</description></item><item><title>El mapa Logístico</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/modelizaci%C3%B3n-de-sistemas-biol%C3%B3gicos/logistic-map/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/modelizaci%C3%B3n-de-sistemas-biol%C3%B3gicos/logistic-map/</guid><description>El ejercicio que se presenta a continuación se refiere al análisis de una de las ecuaciones presentadas en las diapositivas de la Lección 1, utilizando los métodos hasta ahora aprendidos y toda la información adicional que sea necesaria. La función elegida es el mapa del cubo:
$$x_{n+1} = r \cdot x_{n}^2 \cdot (1 - x_{n})$$ En primer lugar, debemos identificar las regiones de parámetros que producen una dinámica significativa. Suponiendo que r &amp;gt; 0, la mayor descendencia posible se produce cuando la función se maximiza; es decir, cuando su derivada = 0 así:</description></item></channel></rss>