<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Biología Programable on Pablo Marcos' Blog</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/biolog%C3%ADa-programable/</link><description>Recent content in Biología Programable on Pablo Marcos' Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/biolog%C3%ADa-programable/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Studing the CoViD-19 pandemic using space-sensitive compartmental models</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/biolog%C3%ADa-programable/essay/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/biolog%C3%ADa-programable/essay/</guid><description>Absctract In Alóndiga et al, our team presented a modified SEIR model, which we called &amp;ldquo;SEIRHCM&amp;rdquo;, to model the effect of mobility restrictions on deaths during the first wave of the CoViD-19 pandemic. In this paper, we build on that model, extending it to cover the 2 years of the pandemic so far, and trying to add other interesting features, such as waning immunity after 3 months. We have also added a spatial component to the model, representing the 20 most populated provinces in Spain by means of a graph that indicates the interconnections between them.</description></item><item><title>ELIXIO : a synthetic microbial consortium for sustainable violet fragrances</title><link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/biolog%C3%ADa-programable/presentation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/es/posts/master-en-biolog%C3%ADa-computacional/biolog%C3%ADa-programable/presentation/</guid><description>For our presentation, we told the class about ELIXIO, an iGEM 2021 awarded project on developing sustainaible alternatives to the fragances world. It was developed by a team from INSA Toulouse, France. Their work, including this post&amp;rsquo;s header, falls under the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 License.
You can download the PDF here.
Previous Next &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Page: /</description></item></channel></rss>